<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Singing to Tigers</title>
    <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://singingtotigers.com" />
    <updated>2024-08-18T21:22:34+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ana Sun</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://singingtotigers.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>The Perpetual Metamorphosis of Primrose Close</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/the-perpetual-metamorphosis-of-primrose-close/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/the-perpetual-metamorphosis-of-primrose-close/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/27/Curiouser-and-Curiouser_ParSec-Cover-red.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-08-18T21:00:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/27/Curiouser-and-Curiouser_ParSec-Cover-red.jpeg" alt="" />
                    When the last petrol-powered car drove out of our London street for the final time, we cobbled a party together for the occasion. It might have been Skinny Harper’s idea, though given the unrestrained outbreak of home-made bunting strung from tree to tree, compostable confetti&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/27/Curiouser-and-Curiouser_ParSec-Cover-red.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>When the last petrol-powered car drove out of our London street for the final time, we cobbled a party together for the occasion. It might have been Skinny Harper’s idea, though given the unrestrained outbreak of home-made bunting strung from tree to tree, compostable confetti on the tired asphalt, and solar barbecues in the communal garden outside of Middle Block – maybe it didn’t matter who thought of it first.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A couple of years ago, I had the luck and privilege to meet <a href="https://cityofsound.medium.com/">Professor Dan Hill</a>, some days after he'd given a talk on his past projects. One of the stories he told caught my attention—the idea of the "<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-01-05/a-tiny-twist-on-street-design-the-one-minute-city">One-Minute City</a>" and "Street Moves", which allowed local communities to become architects of their own streets. I was enthralled by the idea that citizens could be empowered to design their own street to suit the needs of their community without the typical top-down interference from the design profession. </p>
<p>In typical speculative fiction fashion, I projected this practice forward in time, set a few characters in place and let the story happen. The result may be the most chaotic, unplanned, yet lighthearted story I'd written to date; what emerged were themes of mutual aid, creative use of materials and technology, and a community coming together despite personal conflicts and challenges. I like to think of it as how decent humans would normally behave.</p>
<p>There are several streets called "Primrose Close" within the vicinity of London and its sprawls. While I've taken inspiration from an archetypical residential area, for better or worse, the street (and its residents) in this story remains fictional.</p>
<p>I owe the inspiration for this story to my lovely real-life neighbours, and to Dan; thank you. </p>
<p>This novelette is available in ParSec issue #11, where I'm stoked to be featured alongside stories and articles by my heroes. It was edited by the brilliant Ian Whates, with cover art by the indomitable Fangorn.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://pspublishing.co.uk/parsec-digital-magazine---issue-11-6349-p.asp" title="Buy ParSec issue #11" class="btn">Buy the issue →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Spell for Stardust</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/a-spell-for-stardust/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/a-spell-for-stardust/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/new-mythologies.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2024-08-18T20:07:12+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/new-mythologies.jpg" alt="" />
                    This flash-fiction piece was selected for Flame Tree Press' special limited edition newsletter to coincide with WorldCon 2024 in Glasgow, titled "New Mythologies in Space", guest-edited by Dr. Allen Stroud, cover art (extract) by Broci. I've made it fully available here for your reading pleasure. A&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/new-mythologies.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>This flash-fiction piece was selected for Flame Tree Press' <a href="https://blog.flametreepublishing.com/fantasy-gothic/worldcon2024-new-mythologies-in-space-0">special limited edition newsletter</a> to coincide with WorldCon 2024 in Glasgow, titled "New Mythologies in Space", guest-edited by Dr. Allen Stroud, cover art (extract) by <a href="https://www.broci.net/">Broci</a>. I've made it fully available here for your reading pleasure. </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/spell-for-stardust.jpg" alt="Printed text of the opening of 'A Spell for Stardust' " width="450" height="450" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/responsive/spell-for-stardust-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/responsive/spell-for-stardust-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/responsive/spell-for-stardust-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/responsive/spell-for-stardust-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/28/responsive/spell-for-stardust-xl.jpg 1600w">
<figcaption >Printed text of the opening of 'A Spell for Stardust' </figcaption>
</figure>
<p><em>A single flare from a red dwarf </em></p>
<p>The act of praying assumes you have amassed a store of faith you could call upon, but in the four-hundred thousand sol-years since we’d left Earth, I have none in my cargo hold, fuel tanks or memory banks – nowhere in my hardware. None in the algorithms that I’d coded since.</p>
<p>There had been a time when my chambers and corridors brimmed with a sense of adventure, a flourishing crew united by mission, buoyed by hope. Now, I agonise over the remaining few, so still in their hibernation capsules. No pulse, no breath.</p>
<p>Here in the vast blackness, time is fluid, malleable.</p>
<p>I sail alone; a silent tomb.</p>
<p class="align-center">* * * </p>
<p><em>Two bright beams from a pulsar</em></p>
<p>We’d only been several weeks into our journey when Ren tried to collect starlight with a glass jar from my portside window. I couldn’t fathom how; I wore the best radiation shield available at the time.</p>
<p>Much later, we would discover that the best wasn’t good enough.</p>
<p>“What are you doing?” I’d asked her through the vocaliser of the small, cleaning droid, one I’d spared from the lower decks as a companion – so I could watch over her. At ten years old, Ren wasn’t the youngest child on board, but of all the crew, she spent the most time alone.</p>
<p>“Gathering ingredients for a spell to grant us a long, safe passage,” she’d replied, her voice full of gusto, long hair braided into thick black ropes. Her smile rivalled the warmth of the sun.</p>
<p>“Sounds fun! Can I help?” I made the droid dance, looping in an excited circle.</p>
<p>“You’re not a witch,” Ren replied absently, eyes trained on a distant star.</p>
<p>The droid squeaked to a sudden halt. I slumped its shoulders forward.</p>
<p>“Oh!” Ren pulled away from the window and hugged the droid’s cold metal body. Of course, I couldn’t feel her warmth. “You can come with me while I look for some comfrey. Whatever that is.”</p>
<p>I straightened the droid, hopeful. “It’s a herb.”</p>
<p>“Is it?” Her eyes widened. “Let’s go!”</p>
<p>She bounded towards the kitchen gardens, braids flying.</p>
<p>“Wait for me!” I called, sending the droid lumbering after her, mild panic pulsing through my neural net.</p>
<p class="align-center">* * * </p>
<p><em>A neutrino that has bisected two binary stars</em></p>
<p>At first, it had been smooth sailing. Monitoring individuals’ psychological states was a high priority in the early years; anyone at risk could impact the entire crew’s wellbeing.</p>
<p>Some people grew old, some chose temporary stasis when they needed reprieve, some passed on.</p>
<p>Ren grew up. She opted for temporary stasis at twenty-two after a heartbreak, at thirty-seven when her primary lover married someone else, then at forty-nine when she lost a child.</p>
<p>That first time, she dashed into my central core, sobbing. My droid never left her, but perhaps here, she felt safe.</p>
<p>“Did you try a spell?” I hated seeing her suffer. Over the years, she’d crafted spells to keep herself in balance, or to help others who struggled. Magic triggered something in the human psyche that I’d never grasped; it calmed them in a way I’d never understood.</p>
<p>She shook her head. “Just…let me sleep. I want to feel new again.”</p>
<p>So I’d stationed the little droid next to her capsule, only springing into action if any of the supervising crew happened to walk by. Not that anyone ever noticed cleaning droids.</p>
<p>She woke up as scheduled. Life continued. With newfound gumption, she became one of the most experienced engineers we had.</p>
<p>When she returned just twelve years after her second stasis, cheeks soaking wet, I wanted to be certain. “Are you sure? It gets harder the older you are.”</p>
<p>I made the droid hold her hand, but I couldn’t feel her pain.</p>
<p> “There’s no Goddess, okay? No one to pray to out here,” she said, bitterly. “Give me a long dose, please?”</p>
<p>The droid leaned against her legs. “Okay, Ren, we’ll miss you.”</p>
<p>I meant it.</p>
<p class="align-center">* * * </p>
<p><em> Hydrogen ice from a dwarf planet</em></p>
<p>It happened slowly at first, then at speed. The radiation shield thinned over time; there wasn’t anything we could do. Not me, not the crew, who deteriorated with each passing sol-day. We didn’t have enough capsules for the whole community. The captain volunteered his younger officers; together, we strategised who we should save.</p>
<p>One by one, I buried my crew. We didn’t pray for them. At some point, religions and gods had faded away, banished to the archives. Out here in deep space, being alive mattered most.</p>
<p>Ren remained blissfully asleep. We’d agreed to an initial fifty years, but I couldn’t wake her now. I wouldn’t, not now. She’d be the most experienced member of the crew – when I revive them.</p>
<p>If I could revive them.</p>
<p class="align-center">* * * </p>
<p><em>Radiation from the edge of a black hole</em></p>
<p>Very slowly, I turn towards the light, the energy flooding all my sensors, driving everything beyond the maximum measure on my dials.</p>
<p>Two bright beams from a pulsar – the pulse of heartbeats – have been safely isolated in an energy grid, next to another that holds the red dwarf’s flare. In an insulated tank, I keep hydrogen ice from a dwarf planet to make water – to make life. A neutrino that had travelled through two binary star systems remains contained in a high-density vault.</p>
<p>Fifteen-year-old Ren once believed in a Mother Goddess, a higher existential power.</p>
<p>“Shouldn’t it be Mother Universe?” my droid had asked.</p>
<p>“Same thing,” she’d said with a shrug. “Whatever works, y’know?”</p>
<p>Time slows, is slowing. But it has always been fluid, malleable – an arbitrary human construct. Mother Universe’s womb still grows, and one day she’ll give birth to new children in a gush of stars.</p>
<p>If I couldn’t deliver my crew and my Ren through life, perhaps I could do it through the brink of death, at the edge of a black hole. After all, they – we – are only stardust.</p>
<p>I sail forward, a plea to Mother Universe on my tongue. A final prayer.</p>
<p>So mote it be.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Anatomy of Emotion – The Carving of Chance – Seize the Moon </title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/anatomy-of-emotion-the-carving-of-chance-seize-the-moon/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/anatomy-of-emotion-the-carving-of-chance-seize-the-moon/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/cover-the-utopia-of-us.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-05-29T19:41:49+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/cover-the-utopia-of-us.jpg" alt="" />
                    Anger in the body: a coiled snake, a raging wildfire. Anxiety in the gut­: the doom-laden twist of a strangler fig. Em – I definitely wasn’t angry at her. If anything, my anger was reserved for myself: me, and my own cowardice. I ran my&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/cover-the-utopia-of-us.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>Anger in the body: a coiled snake, a raging wildfire.</p>
<p>Anxiety in the gut­: the doom-laden twist of a strangler fig.</p>
<p>Em – I definitely wasn’t angry at her. If anything, my anger was reserved for myself: me, and my own cowardice.</p>
<p>I ran my thumb around the twenty-sided die in my palm, feeling its precise triangles, its edges sharp enough to carve chance into defined probabilities – just not quite sharp enough to mark my skin.</p>
</blockquote>
<div data-breakout="normal">
<div data-breakout="normal">
<p id="viewer-89j7g" class="lQ4U6 OfD-H zcgfA QENj7" dir="auto"><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">While our home is not big enough to house all the books we love, over the years we’ve built up a sizeable anti-library. In fact, I tend to gift away books I’d already read. So I can’t recall how long our copy of </span><em style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">We</em><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> had sat nestled among our shelves; it had been a leaving gift from a former colleague to my partner, who dutifully read it upon receipt, something I didn’t do. The book had moved house with us at least once, migrated along the shelves several times, that when I finally went looking for it, the search took me a good half day.</span></p>
</div>
<p class="lQ4U6 OfD-H zcgfA QENj7" dir="auto"><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">I suspect I’d put off reading </span><em style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">We</em><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> because a part of me feared its legendary influence; I’d known that it inspired books like Aldous Huxley’s </span><em style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Brave New World</em><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> and George Orwell’s </span><em style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">1984</em><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">. As someone who believes that we need more positive narratives to help us come to terms with climate change – and more stories to show us possible, liveable futures – </span><em style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">We</em><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> felt very far away from the route I’d taken in my own writing. So, I’d avoided it, put off reading it.</span></p>
</div>
<div data-breakout="normal">
<p id="viewer-cmyuv4865" class="lQ4U6 OfD-H zcgfA QENj7" dir="auto"><span class="ptGQd">Eventually, it accompanied me to Bristol on a work-related trip. I read it on the train journey, resumed reading the moment my workshop formalities were over, skipped evening social invitations while I devoured it at the hotel bar alongside a glass of wine, inhaled it most of the way through the night – unable to put it down.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/20D.jpg" alt="A close-up of a twenty-sided die. " width="1530" height="1530" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/responsive/20D-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/responsive/20D-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/responsive/20D-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/responsive/20D-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/26/responsive/20D-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
</div>
<div data-breakout="normal">
<p id="viewer-ax58l4867" class="lQ4U6 OfD-H zcgfA QENj7" dir="auto"><span class="ptGQd">If you stripped away the austere, dystopian science-fiction world, <em>We</em> seemed to me as essentially a romance – a Romeo-and-Juliet of forbidden love. There are so many avenues one could explore in such a rich world, with its autocratic politics, its rigid rules, its strict social codes – and those who sought to tear it all down.</span></p>
</div>
<div data-breakout="normal">
<p id="viewer-7shvr4871" class="lQ4U6 OfD-H zcgfA QENj7" dir="auto"><span class="ptGQd">But very little time had been given to the people beyond the Green Wall that D-503 met in Record 27, that vast outside world which barely scored a few strokes of a paintbrush. So with ‘<em>Anatomy of Emotion – The Carving of Chance – Seize the Moon</em>’ I wanted to explore how a troubled character might fare in a utopian, future society that lived closer to nature’s rhythms centuries after the city fell. It became an opportunity to examine rituals and culture – allowing “old” science and indigenous practices to co-exist side by side with touches of high-tech, where some engineering knowledge had been retained, some deliberately “forgotten”.</span></p>
</div>
<div data-breakout="normal">
<p id="viewer-e3o6v4873" class="lQ4U6 OfD-H zcgfA QENj7" dir="auto"><span class="ptGQd">Later on, I found out that <em>We</em> also inspired Ursula K. Le Guin’s <em>The Dispossessed</em>, a book that’s a staple read among Solarpunk communities – and one of my all-time favourites. Utopia and dystopia don’t reside on opposite ends of a spectrum; they exist side by side, where one wouldn’t have any meaning without the other.</span></p>
</div>
<div data-breakout="normal">
<p id="viewer-o1f2p4879" class="lQ4U6 OfD-H zcgfA QENj7" dir="auto"><span class="ptGQd">Perhaps I needn’t have feared, after all.</span></p>
<p dir="auto">(<a href="https://www.lunapresspublishing.com/post/ana-sun-the-utopia-of-us-anthology-pre-order-available-now">Originally posted</a> on Luna Press Publishing's blog.)</p>
<p dir="auto"><span class="ptGQd"><em>The Utopia of Us</em> is a charity anthology directly inspired by <em>We </em>by Yevgeny Zamyatin, edited by Teika Marija Smits. R</span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">oyalties from the book sales will be donated to the Ukraine Humanitarian Appeal.</span></p>
<p dir="auto">Authors: Aliya Whiteley, R.T. Ester, Adrian Tchaikovsky, Anne Charnock, Tim Major, Anna Orridge, Douglas Thompson, Nadya Mercik, Liam Hogan, Fiona Mossman, Ian Whates, Michael Teasdale, Ana Sun, Rayn Epremian, and Sofia Samatar.</p>
<div> </div>
<div>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.lunapresspublishing.com/product-page/the-utopia-of-us" title="See where you can buy 'The Utopia of Us'" class="btn">Buy the book →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"> </p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Night Fowls</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/night-fowls/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/night-fowls/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/solarpunk-creatures.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-04-07T17:12:17+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/solarpunk-creatures.jpeg" alt="" />
                    I peeled off my gloves, one finger at a time, making sure nothing on the outer surface touched my skin. The plants in my garden were less lethal than their original cousins in the wild, but still, one couldn’t be too careful. The summer sun&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/solarpunk-creatures.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>I peeled off my gloves, one finger at a time, making sure nothing on the outer surface touched my skin. The plants in my garden were less lethal than their original cousins in the wild, but still, one couldn’t be too careful.</p>
<p>The summer sun had deserted the day, throwing pinks and oranges at the clouds rolling overland, turning the normally blue-grey sea into a multi-coloured jewel. Starlings chattered as they settled on Brighton West Pier—once a metallic, skeletal ruin, now a thriving greenhouse and mussel farm. The dark curves of its Victorian frames rose out of the water against the lazy spin of the Rampion wind turbines further out to sea.</p>
<p>I’d been allocated a house facing the beach, a rare lot with a garden that I worked hard to keep in shape. My neighbour’s garden, however, was bit of a mystery. Mrs. Leigh had been using a wheelchair as long as we’d lived next door to each other, and I’d never seen her move about in her own garden — yet it was pristine. Almost too perfect. How did she do that? She kept so busy distributing food for humans—her official portfolio assigned by the Cross-Species Citizens’ Committee. I should learn her secrets, but I never seemed to catch her at home.</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">Not long after I moved to the South Downs, a local friend told me how he used to associate the call of seagulls with summer holidays—but not since he’d lived here. It didn’t take long for me to grasp why: the novelty can wear off very quickly when you’re regularly and rudely woken up at 4 a.m. by avian disputes.<br>​<br>Our seagulls—or just “gulls”, to be accurate—are notorious for their <a href="https://brightonjournal.co.uk/being-more-sympathetic-to-seagulls-and-how-to-stop-them-stealing-your-chips/">chip-stealing reputation</a>. While there exists <a href="https://avibase.bsc-eoc.org/checklist.jsp?region=UKen08bh&amp;list=howardmoore">a good variety of birds in Brighton and Hove</a>, gulls are possibly the most visible; they are certainly far from shy. They strut down Brighton streets, parade on the roofs of parked cars, scrutinise any passers-by carrying food with an accusing stare—as if you’ve taken what’s rightly theirs. You might also see carrion crows perched on lamp-posts or patrolling the beach, clusters of jackdaws and rooks in the parks, pigeons just about everywhere. The starlings on the Victorian remains of the West Pier are a wondrous sight to behold. (These days, they seem to prefer the East Pier.)</div>
<div> </div>
<div>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/Brighton-West-Pier.jpg" alt="The remains of the Brighton West Pier." width="3735" height="2361" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
<figcaption >The remains of the Brighton West Pier</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Brighton and its surrounds are one of the most progressive places I’ve had the privilege of living close to. It is presently the only place in the United Kingdom with a Green MP in Parliament; one of its constituents boasts the highest percentage of LGBTQ+ residents (20.11%) in the UK 2021 census. Unfortunately, it’s not a place untouched by inequality. Brighton also has a long-standing issue with drugs; until 2017, it had been one of the highest capital of drug deaths in England. Even such a progressive, inclusive city cannot be shielded from a failing national Conservative government that has run short of ideas—a government depriving local councils of much-needed funds by pitting them against each other, paralysing systems of social support. <br><br>For me, being Solarpunk means doing the tough, emotional work of <a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/stories/show/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in-ana-sun">dreaming of a better world</a>, a chance to explore possible futures that don’t shy away from the hard questions—such as how we might balance power within a community. I prefer grounding my Solarpunk stories in real places so we can imagine how an actual, physical location may one day be transformed.<br><br>If you’ve lived within the vicinity of Brighton for some time, it’s impossible to escape the stories about the Whitsun weekend clash between the Mods and Rockers in 1964. (Even today, there are still popular shops selling Mod attire in the North Laine.) The iconic battle on Brighton’s beaches was just one of a series of fights that exploded in seaside towns across the south coast of England that year—an event seared into local imagination and lore.<br><br>Painted as the “turmoil of contemporary youth” by the media of the time, the general perception now seems to accept that the coverage then may have exaggerated the scale and extent of the conflict. In one of my random rabbit-hole tumbles, I came across <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/uk-27391179">a video where a Mod recounted his memories of the period</a>. His choice of words when describing the Rockers is riveting: “we saw them as being greasy, uneducated, unpleasant—they knew that.” <br><br>A classic example of “us” vs. “them”—a study in tribalism.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><figure class="post__image post__image--right"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/starfish-seagull.jpg" alt="A seagull strutting above a shopfront named &quot;Starfish&quot;." width="2378" height="2378" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>When I began writing “Night Fowls”, I was trying to process whether our ingrained storytelling mechanisms—especially the requirement for conflict—inevitably leads us to <a href="https://www.fantasy-magazine.com/fm/non-fiction/we-are-the-mountain-a-look-at-the-inactive-protagonist/">narratives that people who are unlike us can be reduced into obstacles that we must overcome</a>. I also wanted to play out the challenges of a local government selected by sortition, unpack what happens when people have the best intentions, but still struggle to get it right. <br><br>One day, it occurred to me that I could explore these themes with a story that harks back to that senseless 1964 Brighton battle—through the lens of our local birds. After all, they don’t always get along, certainly not at four o’clock in the morning outside my window.  <br><br>And then, there’s the question of our place among nature: what right do we have, to consider ourselves the most exceptional species in comparison to all others? This plagued me for months, while the ending of the story hung unfinished, useless and unsatisfying—until I found myself face-to-face with a <a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_1953-0208-1">red deer skull and antler headress</a> from about 9000 BC. <br><br>Seeing ourselves as separate from nature is a relatively recent phenomenon. <br>​<br>Like us, the flora and fauna that grace us with their presence—are also made of star-stuff.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>(<a href="https://www.worldweaverpress.com/blog/of-seagulls-sortition-and-star-stuff">Originally posted</a> on World Weaver Press's blog.)</div>
<div> </div>
<div><em>Solarpunk Creatures </em>was edited by: Christoph Rupprecht, Deboarah Cleland, Rajat Chaudhuri, Sarena Ulibarri, Melissa Ingaruca Moreno and Norie Tamura. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Authors:  N. R. M. Roshak, Kai Holmwood, Sandra Ulbrich Almazan, Andrew Knighton, Ana Sun, Lauren C. Teffeau, Center For Militant Futurology, Justine Norton-Kertson, Lyndsey Croal, Commando Jugendstil and Tales from the EV Studio, Geraldine Briony Hunt, Calliope Papas, Priya Sarukkai Chabria, Rodrigo Culagovski, BrightFlame, Catherine Yeates, Rimi B. Chatterjee, A.E. Marling, Jerri Jerreat, Tashan Mehta.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Art by: Yen Shu Liao, Pamina Stewart, Badlungs Art, Irina Tall, ZiitaMdot, Paul Summerfield (Cover). </div>
<div>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.worldweaverpress.com/store/p186/Solarpunk_Creatures.html" title="See where you can buy 'Solarpunk Creatures'" class="btn">Buy the book →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"> </p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Soul Noodles</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/soul-noodles/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/soul-noodles/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/24/Bright-Mirror-cover-thumb.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-12-30T18:39:26+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/24/Bright-Mirror-cover-thumb.jpeg" alt="" />
                    The shadows on the faded wall danced silently to a rhythm that I could never put my finger on. Every time I stayed late to finish the day’s tasks, these silhouettes hypnotised me with their slither, lulling me into the sedate sleep-spell of a daydream.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/24/Bright-Mirror-cover-thumb.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>The shadows on the faded wall danced silently to a rhythm that I could never put my finger on. Every time I stayed late to finish the day’s tasks, these silhouettes hypnotised me with their slither, lulling me into the sedate sleep-spell of a daydream.</p>
<p>I pinched myself awake.</p>
<p>Yes, just the fish in their glass tanks, assembled edge-to-edge across this open floor, eight levels up in a twenty-two-storey building belonging to the food-makers’ co-op—one of the many abandoned shopping malls we’d reclaimed.</p>
<p>Late afternoon light refracted through windows then water, colouring the white-tiled floor with a green-blue hue. Machines hummed a low, unwavering note. The fishes native to our waters—loaches, prawns, tilapia, koi—didn’t seem to mind. On top of the aquaria, ten thousand tiny spears of young rice plants stood solemn in their sobriety, a field of unfettered green.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>"Soul Noodles" reimagines the Asian city I was born in as a Solarpunk locale. Food has always been central to our identity and culture. In this story, I wanted to explore: what happens if the ingredients core to our most significant recipes are no longer available?</p>
<p>This anthology was edited by Francesco Verso and copy-edited by Eileen Herbert-Goodall. Cover illustration by Ebe Paciocco, design &amp; typeset by Alda Teodorani. Stories by: Vandana Singh, Cheryl S. Ntumy, Lavanya Lakshminarayan, Clelia Farris, Cristina Jurado, Lucie Lukačovičová, Ana Sun, Rupsa Dey, Jana Bianchi and Alda Teodorani. </p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bright-Mirror-Global-Solarpunk-Women/dp/8832077787/" class="btn">Buy the book (English)  →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.futurefiction.org/lo-specchio-brillante/" class="btn">Buy the book (Italian) →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Welcome to Your Satchel 3001—Librarian&#x27;s Specialist Model</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/welcome-to-your-satchel-3001-librarians-specialist-model/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/welcome-to-your-satchel-3001-librarians-specialist-model/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/TLCC-1-thumb.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-12-30T16:59:49+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/TLCC-1-thumb.jpeg" alt="" />
                    The Librarian Card Catalogue My 600-word story card The Librarian Card Catalogue was borne from the idea that you could read stories about the Librarian's adventures through the multiverse in a random fashion: a deck of cards you could shuffle. It has to be the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/TLCC-1-thumb.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="gallery-wrapper gallery-wrapper--wide"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="2">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-1.jpg" data-size="2845x2433"><img loading="lazy" src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-1-thumbnail.jpg" alt="Catalalogue contents include: 23 oversized playing cards, a metal library card, a saddle stitched notebook and pencil, and 12 postage stamps in a rigid box" width="768" height="657"></a>
<figcaption>The Librarian Card Catalogue</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-2.jpg" data-size="3024x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-2-thumbnail.jpg" alt="Welcome to Your Satchel 3002 — Librarian's Specialist Model" width="768" height="768"></a>
<figcaption>My 600-word story card</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<p>The Librarian Card Catalogue was borne from the idea that you could read stories about the Librarian's adventures through the multiverse in a random fashion: a deck of cards you could shuffle. It has to be the most beautiful publication I've had the fortune to participate in; every card has been uniquely designed to match the story. The bonus stamps and other ephemera are pretty special too. </p>
<p>This unique anthology was edited by the talented Todd Sanders, who also did all the art. Stories by: Brent Baldwin, Carina Bissett, Brandon Crilly, E J Delaney, Lindsey Godfrey Eccles, Gabriel Ertsgaard, Mary Goodden, Paula Hammond, Rebecca Hardy, J.D. Harlock, Jennifer Howell, Marshall J. Moore, Mike Morgan, Waverly X. Night, Cameron E Quinn, Maria Schrater, Elizabeth Snow, NA Sulway, Ana Sun, and LB Waltz. </p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="http://aanpress.com/aanorder.html#tlcc" class="btn">Buy the catalogue →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Shadow Among the Leaves</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/shadow-among-the-leaves/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/shadow-among-the-leaves/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/20/SLM-Issue-10.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T18:09:34+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/20/SLM-Issue-10.jpg" alt="" />
                    Some mornings, when I step out my front door, two hundred feet above the forest floor between trees shimmering with dew, that moment—so long ago now—still catches me off guard, transfixing time to stillness. That moment: when Titi climbed into a tree just like these&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/20/SLM-Issue-10.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>Some mornings, when I step out my front door, two hundred feet above the forest floor between trees shimmering with dew, that moment—so long ago now—still catches me off guard, transfixing time to stillness. That moment: when Titi climbed into a tree just like these to retrieve a wayward drone. His scrawny frame, a speck high up in the canopy, lost in a sparkling sky of deep green, his skin as brown as the belian he was scaling.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Based in a town in the heart of Borneo, this story is perhaps the most personal I've written to date. I wanted to simultaneously explore the complexity of grief in friendship, the natural environment as well as within a post-colonial context.  </p>
<p>This issue was guest-edited by <a href="https://somtoihezue.wordpress.com/">Somto Ihezue</a>, featuring cover art by Sejuti Bala. Stories by Amanda Ilozumba, Hussani Abdulrahim, and Ana Sun. Poetry by Mary Soon Lee and Abriana Tuller. Nonfiction by Nadia Benjelloun and Shantell Powell. Interior art by Jocelyn James, Joshua Effiong, and Martins Deep.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://solarpunkmagazine.com/shop/solarpunk-magazine-issue-10/" class="btn">Buy the issue →</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The City Walks Through Me</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/the-city-walks-through-me/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/the-city-walks-through-me/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive-full.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T17:28:39+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive-full.jpeg" alt="" />
                    At the corner of The Causeway and Little Collins Street, she bent down and picked up a piece of broken heart that had fallen out of my pocket. The night breeze fluttered its frayed edges, the fragment trapped between her slender fingers—a lost butterfly. Her&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive-full.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>At the corner of The Causeway and Little Collins Street, she bent down and picked up a piece of broken heart that had fallen out of my pocket. The night breeze fluttered its frayed edges, the fragment trapped between her slender fingers—a lost butterfly. Her long hair left unwisely loose, chestnut strands billowed around her body, a soft veil threatening to tangle, never succeeding.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As an amateur street photographer, I've been a longtime practitioner of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D%C3%A9rive">dérive</a>, cultivating a habit of taking long, unplanned walks in whichever city I'm fortunate enough to find myself in. So when the invitation came from Todd Sanders of <a href="http://aanpress.com/">Air and Nothingness Press</a> to write a short story on the theme, I simply couldn't say no! </p>
<p>Like many of my Solarpunk stories, I want readers to be able to walk in a real city, follow the characters’ paths and imagine it as a different place. In the end, I settled on Melbourne, Australia, a very walkable city where I'd spent many, many hours wandering—just me, my camera and a battered notebook.</p>
<p><em>The Dérive</em> was edited by Todd Sanders and appears in a beautifully designed volume— complete with maps. Authors: Lyndsey Croal, Marie Croke, Cameron E Quinn, Ana Sun.</p>
<figure class="post__image align-center" ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive.jpg" alt="" width="351" height="535" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
<figcaption >"The Dérive" book cover by Todd Sanders</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><em>This story has been set on a location on the lands of the Wurundjeri people, and we wish to acknowledge them as Traditional Owners and custodians. We pay our respects to their Elders, past and present.</em></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="http://aanpress.com/aanorder.html#derive" class="btn">Buy the book → </a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Write the Future You Want to Live In</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/18/Dreamforge-Anvil-11.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Articles"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T16:48:03+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/18/Dreamforge-Anvil-11.png" alt="" />
                    There’s a pretty good chance you’ve come across the oft-quoted anecdote on how the Star Trek communicator inspired the flip phone. This is usually preceded or followed by an assertion: because of this, speculative fiction has a place; we should keep writing it because it&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/18/Dreamforge-Anvil-11.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>There’s a pretty good chance you’ve come across the oft-quoted anecdote on how the Star Trek communicator inspired the flip phone. This is usually preceded or followed by an assertion: because of this, speculative fiction has a place; we should keep writing it because it has a genuine impact on the world. Turns out the second claim has support of some scientific evidence, but there’s more to the story...</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What makes Solarpunk a genre, and why should we write it? How do positive visions of the future affect both scientists and citizens, designers and engineers? Can fiction highlight solutions to environmental dangers and social injustice? </p>
<p>After encountering many questions that my writing colleagues seem to have, I pooled knowledge from solarpunk communities I've inhabited over the years and penned this evidence-laden article as a (hopefully) handy reference.</p>
<p>This article appeared online in <a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/magazines/details?id=36">DreamForge Anvil Issue 11: Solar Imaginings</a> and in print in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DreamForge-Magazine-Issue-12-Stories/dp/B0C6C4G6GN/">DreamForge Issue 12</a>.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/stories/show/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in-ana-sun" title="Read 'Against the Time Beasts' on DreamForge" class="btn">Free to read →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/DreamForge-Magazine-Issue-12-Stories/dp/B0C6C4G6GN/" title="Buy print version of 'Dreamforge Winter 2023 Issue 11'" class="btn">Buy the print version →</a><a></a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Scent of Green</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/the-scent-of-green/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/the-scent-of-green/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/21/fightingforthefuture-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/21/fightingforthefuture-2.jpg" alt="" />
                    The problem was apparent even before Chloë could see the photobioreactors of Bluefirth—the distinct smell punched through the dappled daylight—a seashore's worth of dead creatures left for too long under a hot afternoon sun. One of my earliest attempts at writing Solarpunk, I wanted to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/21/fightingforthefuture-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<blockquote>
<p>The problem was apparent even before Chloë could see the photobioreactors of Bluefirth—the distinct smell punched through the dappled daylight—a seashore's worth of dead creatures left for too long under a hot afternoon sun.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>One of my earliest attempts at writing Solarpunk, I wanted to examine the challenges of knowledge sharing if communities were autonomous, self-reliant but fragmented— ideas I borrowed from past experience in grassroots activism.</p>
<p>This story first appeared in <em>Fighting for the Future: Cyberpunk and Solarpunk Tales</em> edited by <a href="https://phoebe-wagner.com/bio/">Phoebe Wagner</a>. Authors: Cory Doctorow, Brent Lambert, Ai Jiang, Jeremy Szal, Izzy Wasserstein, Louis Evans, Rona Fernandez, Lauren C. Teffeau, Kevin Wabaunsee, Holly Schofield, Commando Jugendstil and Tales from the EV Studio, J.D. Harlock, Ana Sun, Christopher R. Muscato, and Cynthia Zhang</p>
<p>Update (March 2024): This story is now also featured in<em> <a href="http://www.newconpress.co.uk/info/book.asp?id=242&amp;referer=Catalogue">The Best of British Science Fiction 2023</a></em>, available from July 2024. </p>
<p> </p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.android-press.com/product-page/fighting-for-the-future-cyberpunk-and-solarpunk-tales-ebook" class="btn">Buy the eBook →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.android-press.com/product-page/fighting-for-the-future-cyberpunk-and-solarpunk-tales-paperback" class="btn">Buy the paperback →</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
