<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Singing to Tigers</title>
    <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://singingtotigers.com" />
    <updated>2023-03-08T19:00:38+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ana Sun</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://singingtotigers.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>About Ana</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/about-ana/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/about-ana/</id>
            <category term="About"/>

        <updated>2023-01-01T22:57:30+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Ana Sun (pronounced “Soon”) writes from the edge of an ancient town along the River Ouse in the south-east of England. She spent her childhood in Malaysian Borneo, and has lived on two other islands prior to moving to the UK. In another life, she&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image page--author__avatar"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/ana-2014-hi-res.jpg" alt="" width="2803" height="2608" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
<p>Ana Sun (pronounced “Soon”) writes from the edge of an ancient town along the River Ouse in the south-east of England. She spent her childhood in Malaysian Borneo, and has lived on two other islands prior to moving to the UK. In another life, she might have been a musician, an anthropologist—or a botanist obsessed with edible flowers.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Contact Me</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/contact-me/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/contact-me/</id>

        <updated>2023-01-22T20:32:33+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Please say hi! Reach out to me via email or find me on Mastodon as @ana@wandering.shop. 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Please say hi! Reach out to me via <a href="hello AT singingtotigers.com" rel="nofollow">email</a> or find me on Mastodon as <a href="https://wandering.shop/@ana" rel="nofollow">@ana@wandering.shop</a>. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>La bibliothèque d&#x27;objets quotidiens</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/la-bibliotheque-d-objets-quotidiens/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/la-bibliotheque-d-objets-quotidiens/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-librarian.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-03-08T19:00:29+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-librarian.jpg" alt="The Librarian (standard cover)" />
                    Is there a moment that you would miss most, across any given lifetime? Sitting here in this hidden street in Montmartre—or at least the memory of it—might well be the moment I’d cling to at my final point of death. When Todd Sanders of Air&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-librarian.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="The Librarian (standard cover)" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>Is there a moment that you would miss most, across any given lifetime?</p>
<p>Sitting here in this hidden street in Montmartre—or at least the memory of it—might well be the moment I’d cling to at my final point of death.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When Todd Sanders of <a href="http://aanpress.com/">Air and Nothing Press</a> made an open call for stories for The Librarian, it came with <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/52625019/the-librarian-1">an intriguing list of character guidelines</a>. This story took inspiration from a real library of things local to me, mashed up with ideas triggered by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Doctor%27s_Wife">a favourite Dr. Who episode</a>. </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2.jpeg" alt="The Librarian (standard cover)" width="500" height="749" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-xs.jpeg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-sm.jpeg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-md.jpeg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-lg.jpeg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-xl.jpeg 1600w"></figure>
<figcaption >"The Librarian" (Standard Book Cover) by Todd Sanders</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="align-right"><a href="http://aanpress.com/aanorder.html#TL" title="Order 'The Librarian' from Air &amp; Nothingness Press" class="btn">Buy the book → </a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Against the Time Beasts</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/against-the-time-beasts/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/against-the-time-beasts/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/11/illustration-202212-against-the-time-beasts.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-01-22T20:27:54+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/11/illustration-202212-against-the-time-beasts.png" alt="" />
                    Sometimes, the future hinges on a whisker of a moment, as if time were a wild animal. That weight in the air as seconds prowl past, I smell it on your breath as you curl and uncurl your fists— left, then right, then left again.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/11/illustration-202212-against-the-time-beasts.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>Sometimes, the future hinges on a whisker of a moment, as if time were a wild animal. That weight in the air as seconds prowl past, I smell it on your breath as you curl and uncurl your fists— left, then right, then left again.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I'm somewhat obsessed by how time wears all things down, including our relationships, commitments and promises to ourselves and to each other. “Against the Time Beasts” is the first of a set of tales where the title of each story corresponds to a line in a poem—examining time, entropy and the moments of minute deaths.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/stories/show/against-the-time-beasts-ana-sun" title="Read 'Against the Time Beasts' on DreamForge" class="btn">Free to Read →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/DreamForge-Magazine-Issue-11-Stories/dp/B0BQ9JB4TK/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3RA7PH9HS3IAJ&amp;keywords=dreamforge+magazine+11&amp;qid=1672193691&amp;sprefix=dreamforge+magazine+11,aps,86&amp;sr=8-1" title="Buy print version of 'Dreamforge Winter 2023 Issue 11'" class="btn">Buy Print Version →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dandelion Brew</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/dandelion-brew/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/dandelion-brew/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/12/Dandelion-Brew-Tangent.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-01-22T20:25:00+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/12/Dandelion-Brew-Tangent.jpg" alt="" />
                    I turn around to prepare the infusions. Something catches my eye. A boat I’ve never seen before slithers into the Serpentine. Unlike mine, its cockpit is covered, presumably connected to the main cabin. The small deck on the bow looks like an afterthought. There are&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/12/Dandelion-Brew-Tangent.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>I turn around to prepare the infusions. Something catches my eye. A boat I’ve never seen before slithers into the Serpentine. Unlike mine, its cockpit is covered, presumably connected to the main cabin. The small deck on the bow looks like an afterthought. There are no windows— it’s all black. It has no running lights, surely a safety hazard if you ask me. It’s ugly and fascinating the way oil slicks are. </p>
</blockquote>
<p>To adapt to our changing climate and overcome challenges, we are going to need everything across the gamut of human knowledge, skills and technology. Too often, I've witnessed people taking sides in believing that their evidence is the only version of truth — whether it's empiricism or folk knowledge — to the extent that we would reject each others' perspectives without listening to each other, because we are blinded by prejudice. Writing "Dandelion Brew" was my way of exploring the relationship between technology and lore, and to play out a tiny slice of this conflict and examine how we might find common ground, and that seeing the world differently, together garners a collective strength.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/stories/show/dandelion-brew-ana-sun" title="Read 'Dandelion Brew' for free on Dreamforge" class="btn">Free to Read →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Rabbit in the Moon</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/rabbit-in-the-moon/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/rabbit-in-the-moon/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/14/cover-2021-ttt-sq.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-03-08T19:00:38+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/14/cover-2021-ttt-sq.jpeg" alt="" />
                    There is a momentary flicker under the garish sign that is flashing Happiness can be yours with a pleasure doll draped over a plush red sofa—a flicker that morphs into an image, then takes the form of a solid white rabbit. It’s so subtle that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/14/cover-2021-ttt-sq.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<blockquote>
<p>There is a momentary flicker under the garish sign that is flashing <em>Happiness can be yours</em> with a pleasure doll draped over a plush red sofa—a flicker that morphs into an image, then takes the form of a solid white rabbit. It’s so subtle that it would’ve been easily missed if I didn’t know what to look for.</p>
</blockquote>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Cyberpunk worlds aren’t usually happy places. They tend to be oppressive technocracies, where people like you and me would probably have very little free will. But then, neither are fairy tales—we’d probably wouldn’t last all that long before being cursed by a witch or eaten by a wolf.</p>
<p>Yet something about the juxtaposition of “cyberpunk” and “fairy tales” summoned me and blinked at me like a full-height, hi-res advertisement in Shinjuku, and I knew I had to write something for Rhonda Parrish’s <em>Trenchcoats, Towers and Trolls</em>. The challenge was just too good to resist.</p>
<p>Next dilemma: which fairy tale? I knew I didn’t want to choose a story from the catalogues of the Brothers Grimm or Hans Christian Andersen. While I grew up with these stories like many other post-colonial children—and loved them—there are so many other folktales that don’t get airtime.</p>
<p>One of my personal goals as a writer is to be truer to my messy identity. A third culture kid who wanted to experience the world, I never made it “home” because “home” no longer made sense. This anthology presented the perfect opportunity for me to reconcile my love for lore, passion for science—and to embrace my uprooted, fragmented self.</p>
<p>The visual aesthetic of cyberpunk today is heavily influenced by<em> Bladerunner</em>, which, Ridley Scott apparently borrowed from “the landscape of Hong Kong on a bad day”. It seemed apt to find a story of Asian origins, which could be transported into a high-tech, futuristic urban setting.</p>
<p>Many non-Western folktales I recall from childhood suffer the same issues as fairy tales; they no longer reflect today’s acceptable values. Others are directly linked to physical landmarks, which would be difficult to translate into the cyberpunk genre without the risk of losing the significance of the tales entirely. Then, there are folktales which feature animals as main characters.</p>
<p>I wish I could tell you that I got a flash of inspiration for “The Rabbit in the Moon” by looking up at the night sky—but it was nothing as romantic as that. I think it because I’d been playing <em>Tsuki’s Adventure</em> on my phone during those funny little time gaps we get in a day. There, the secret is out.</p>
<p>How does one deal with the existence of sweet, gentle animals in such a gritty, dark world? It was tempting to make the characters into cybernetic creatures or street urchins with animal-shaped tattoos, but then one would lose quality and texture of such a folktale—I wanted to somehow keep the innocence and purity that these stories historically have. And so it became a perfect excuse to examine the concept of what is “normal” in a world where data about everything is collected and AI-analysed for potentially nefarious uses. Sadly, a world that’s not so far from the current reality we live in…</p>
<p>But even in such a world, we can look out for one another, and treat each other with respect as fellow creatures under the same night sky. Therein lies the seeds of hope for a better, kinder world.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rhondaparrish.com/home/inspiration-hope-and-a-secret-from-ana-sun/">Originally posted</a> on Rhonda Parish's blog.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.worldweaverpress.com/store/p182/Trenchcoats%2C_Towers%2C_and_Trolls.html" class="btn--white btn">Buy the book →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
