<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Singing to Tigers</title>
    <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://singingtotigers.com" />
    <updated>2024-04-07T17:31:20+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Ana Sun</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://singingtotigers.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Night Fowls</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/night-fowls/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/night-fowls/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/solarpunk-creatures.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-04-07T17:12:17+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/solarpunk-creatures.jpeg" alt="" />
                    I peeled off my gloves, one finger at a time, making sure nothing on the outer surface touched my skin. The plants in my garden were less lethal than their original cousins in the wild, but still, one couldn’t be too careful. The summer sun&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/solarpunk-creatures.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>I peeled off my gloves, one finger at a time, making sure nothing on the outer surface touched my skin. The plants in my garden were less lethal than their original cousins in the wild, but still, one couldn’t be too careful.</p>
<p>The summer sun had deserted the day, throwing pinks and oranges at the clouds rolling overland, turning the normally blue-grey sea into a multi-coloured jewel. Starlings chattered as they settled on Brighton West Pier—once a metallic, skeletal ruin, now a thriving greenhouse and mussel farm. The dark curves of its Victorian frames rose out of the water against the lazy spin of the Rampion wind turbines further out to sea.</p>
<p>I’d been allocated a house facing the beach, a rare lot with a garden that I worked hard to keep in shape. My neighbour’s garden, however, was bit of a mystery. Mrs. Leigh had been using a wheelchair as long as we’d lived next door to each other, and I’d never seen her move about in her own garden — yet it was pristine. Almost too perfect. How did she do that? She kept so busy distributing food for humans—her official portfolio assigned by the Cross-Species Citizens’ Committee. I should learn her secrets, but I never seemed to catch her at home.</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">Not long after I moved to the South Downs, a local friend told me how he used to associate the call of seagulls with summer holidays—but not since he’d lived here. It didn’t take long for me to grasp why: the novelty can wear off very quickly when you’re regularly and rudely woken up at 4 a.m. by avian disputes.<br>​<br>Our seagulls—or just “gulls”, to be accurate—are notorious for their <a href="https://brightonjournal.co.uk/being-more-sympathetic-to-seagulls-and-how-to-stop-them-stealing-your-chips/">chip-stealing reputation</a>. While there exists <a href="https://avibase.bsc-eoc.org/checklist.jsp?region=UKen08bh&amp;list=howardmoore">a good variety of birds in Brighton and Hove</a>, gulls are possibly the most visible; they are certainly far from shy. They strut down Brighton streets, parade on the roofs of parked cars, scrutinise any passers-by carrying food with an accusing stare—as if you’ve taken what’s rightly theirs. You might also see carrion crows perched on lamp-posts or patrolling the beach, clusters of jackdaws and rooks in the parks, pigeons just about everywhere. The starlings on the Victorian remains of the West Pier are a wondrous sight to behold. (These days, they seem to prefer the East Pier.)</div>
<div> </div>
<div><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/Brighton-West-Pier.jpg" alt="The remains of the Brighton West Pier." width="3735" height="2361" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/Brighton-West-Pier-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure></div>
<div> </div>
<div>Brighton and its surrounds are one of the most progressive places I’ve had the privilege of living close to. It is presently the only place in the United Kingdom with a Green MP in Parliament; one of its constituents boasts the highest percentage of LGBTQ+ residents (20.11%) in the UK 2021 census. Unfortunately, it’s not a place untouched by inequality. Brighton also has a long-standing issue with drugs; until 2017, it had been one of the highest capital of drug deaths in England. Even such a progressive, inclusive city cannot be shielded from a failing national Conservative government that has run short of ideas—a government depriving local councils of much-needed funds by pitting them against each other, paralysing systems of social support. <br><br>For me, being Solarpunk means doing the tough, emotional work of <a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/stories/show/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in-ana-sun">dreaming of a better world</a>, a chance to explore possible futures that don’t shy away from the hard questions—such as how we might balance power within a community. I prefer grounding my Solarpunk stories in real places so we can imagine how an actual, physical location may one day be transformed.<br><br>If you’ve lived within the vicinity of Brighton for some time, it’s impossible to escape the stories about the Whitsun weekend clash between the Mods and Rockers in 1964. (Even today, there are still popular shops selling Mod attire in the North Laine.) The iconic battle on Brighton’s beaches was just one of a series of fights that exploded in seaside towns across the south coast of England that year—an event seared into local imagination and lore.<br><br>Painted as the “turmoil of contemporary youth” by the media of the time, the general perception now seems to accept that the coverage then may have exaggerated the scale and extent of the conflict. In one of my random rabbit-hole tumbles, I came across <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/uk-27391179">a video where a Mod recounted his memories of the period</a>. His choice of words when describing the Rockers is riveting: “we saw them as being greasy, uneducated, unpleasant—they knew that.” <br><br>A classic example of “us” vs. “them”—a study in tribalism.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><figure class="post__image post__image--right"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/starfish-seagull.jpg" alt="A seagull strutting above a shopfront named &quot;Starfish&quot;." width="2378" height="2378" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/25/responsive/starfish-seagull-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>When I began writing “Night Fowls”, I was trying to process whether our ingrained storytelling mechanisms—especially the requirement for conflict—inevitably leads us to <a href="https://www.fantasy-magazine.com/fm/non-fiction/we-are-the-mountain-a-look-at-the-inactive-protagonist/">narratives that people who are unlike us can be reduced into obstacles that we must overcome</a>. I also wanted to play out the challenges of a local government selected by sortition, unpack what happens when people have the best intentions, but still struggle to get it right. <br><br>One day, it occurred to me that I could explore these themes with a story that harks back to that senseless 1964 Brighton battle—through the lens of our local birds. After all, they don’t always get along, certainly not at four o’clock in the morning outside my window.  <br><br>And then, there’s the question of our place among nature: what right do we have, to consider ourselves the most exceptional species in comparison to all others? This plagued me for months, while the ending of the story hung unfinished, useless and unsatisfying—until I found myself face-to-face with a <a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_1953-0208-1">red deer skull and antler headress</a> from about 9000 BC. <br><br>Seeing ourselves as separate from nature is a relatively recent phenomenon. <br>​<br>Like us, the flora and fauna that grace us with their presence—are also made of star-stuff.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>(<a href="https://www.worldweaverpress.com/blog/of-seagulls-sortition-and-star-stuff">Originally posted</a> on World Weaver Press's blog.)</div>
<div> </div>
<div><em>Solarpunk Creatures </em>was edited by: Christoph Rupprecht, Deboarah Cleland, Rajat Chaudhuri, Sarena Ulibarri, Melissa Ingaruca Moreno and Norie Tamura. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Authors:  N. R. M. Roshak, Kai Holmwood, Sandra Ulbrich Almazan, Andrew Knighton, Ana Sun, Lauren C. Teffeau, Center For Militant Futurology, Justine Norton-Kertson, Lyndsey Croal, Commando Jugendstil and Tales from the EV Studio, Geraldine Briony Hunt, Calliope Papas, Priya Sarukkai Chabria, Rodrigo Culagovski, BrightFlame, Catherine Yeates, Rimi B. Chatterjee, A.E. Marling, Jerri Jerreat, Tashan Mehta.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Art by: Yen Shu Liao, Pamina Stewart, Badlungs Art, Irina Tall, ZiitaMdot, Paul Summerfield (Cover). </div>
<div>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.worldweaverpress.com/store/p186/Solarpunk_Creatures.html" title="See where you can buy 'Solarpunk Creatures'" class="btn">Buy the book →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"> </p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Soul Noodles</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/soul-noodles/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/soul-noodles/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/24/Bright-Mirror-cover-thumb.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-12-30T18:39:26+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/24/Bright-Mirror-cover-thumb.jpeg" alt="" />
                    The shadows on the faded wall danced silently to a rhythm that I could never put my finger on. Every time I stayed late to finish the day’s tasks, these silhouettes hypnotised me with their slither, lulling me into the sedate sleep-spell of a daydream.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/24/Bright-Mirror-cover-thumb.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>The shadows on the faded wall danced silently to a rhythm that I could never put my finger on. Every time I stayed late to finish the day’s tasks, these silhouettes hypnotised me with their slither, lulling me into the sedate sleep-spell of a daydream.</p>
<p>I pinched myself awake.</p>
<p>Yes, just the fish in their glass tanks, assembled edge-to-edge across this open floor, eight levels up in a twenty-two-storey building belonging to the food-makers’ co-op—one of the many abandoned shopping malls we’d reclaimed.</p>
<p>Late afternoon light refracted through windows then water, colouring the white-tiled floor with a green-blue hue. Machines hummed a low, unwavering note. The fishes native to our waters—loaches, prawns, tilapia, koi—didn’t seem to mind. On top of the aquaria, ten thousand tiny spears of young rice plants stood solemn in their sobriety, a field of unfettered green.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>"Soul Noodles" reimagines the Asian city I was born in as a Solarpunk locale. Food has always been central to our identity and culture. In this story, I wanted to explore: what happens if the ingredients core to our most significant recipes are no longer available?</p>
<p>This anthology was edited by Francesco Verso and copy-edited by Eileen Herbert-Goodall. Cover illustration by Ebe Paciocco, design &amp; typeset by Alda Teodorani. Stories by: Vandana Singh, Cheryl S. Ntumy, Lavanya Lakshminarayan, Clelia Farris, Cristina Jurado, Lucie Lukačovičová, Ana Sun, Rupsa Dey, Jana Bianchi and Alda Teodorani. </p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bright-Mirror-Global-Solarpunk-Women/dp/8832077787/" class="btn">Buy the book (English)  →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.futurefiction.org/lo-specchio-brillante/" class="btn">Buy the book (Italian) →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Welcome to Your Satchel 3001—Librarian&#x27;s Specialist Model</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/welcome-to-your-satchel-3001-librarians-specialist-model/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/welcome-to-your-satchel-3001-librarians-specialist-model/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/TLCC-1-thumb.jpeg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2023-12-30T16:59:49+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/TLCC-1-thumb.jpeg" alt="" />
                    The Librarian Card Catalogue My 600-word story card The Librarian Card Catalogue was borne from the idea that you could read stories about the Librarian's adventures through the multiverse in a random fashion: a deck of cards you could shuffle. It has to be the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/TLCC-1-thumb.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="gallery-wrapper gallery-wrapper--wide"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="2">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-1.jpg" data-size="2845x2433"><img loading="lazy" src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-1-thumbnail.jpg" alt="Catalalogue contents include: 23 oversized playing cards, a metal library card, a saddle stitched notebook and pencil, and 12 postage stamps in a rigid box" width="768" height="657"></a>
<figcaption>The Librarian Card Catalogue</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-2.jpg" data-size="3024x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/23/gallery/TLCC-2-thumbnail.jpg" alt="Welcome to Your Satchel 3002 — Librarian's Specialist Model" width="768" height="768"></a>
<figcaption>My 600-word story card</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<p>The Librarian Card Catalogue was borne from the idea that you could read stories about the Librarian's adventures through the multiverse in a random fashion: a deck of cards you could shuffle. It has to be the most beautiful publication I've had the fortune to participate in; every card has been uniquely designed to match the story. The bonus stamps and other ephemera are pretty special too. </p>
<p>This unique anthology was edited by the talented Todd Sanders, who also did all the art. Stories by: Brent Baldwin, Carina Bissett, Brandon Crilly, E J Delaney, Lindsey Godfrey Eccles, Gabriel Ertsgaard, Mary Goodden, Paula Hammond, Rebecca Hardy, J.D. Harlock, Jennifer Howell, Marshall J. Moore, Mike Morgan, Waverly X. Night, Cameron E Quinn, Maria Schrater, Elizabeth Snow, NA Sulway, Ana Sun, and LB Waltz. </p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="http://aanpress.com/aanorder.html#tlcc" class="btn">Buy the catalogue →</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Shadow Among the Leaves</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/shadow-among-the-leaves/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/shadow-among-the-leaves/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/20/SLM-Issue-10.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T18:09:34+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/20/SLM-Issue-10.jpg" alt="" />
                    Some mornings, when I step out my front door, two hundred feet above the forest floor between trees shimmering with dew, that moment—so long ago now—still catches me off guard, transfixing time to stillness. That moment: when Titi climbed into a tree just like these&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/20/SLM-Issue-10.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>Some mornings, when I step out my front door, two hundred feet above the forest floor between trees shimmering with dew, that moment—so long ago now—still catches me off guard, transfixing time to stillness. That moment: when Titi climbed into a tree just like these to retrieve a wayward drone. His scrawny frame, a speck high up in the canopy, lost in a sparkling sky of deep green, his skin as brown as the belian he was scaling.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Based in a town in the heart of Borneo, this story is perhaps the most personal I've written to date. I wanted to simultaneously explore the complexity of grief in friendship, the natural environment as well as within a post-colonial context.  </p>
<p>This issue was guest-edited by <a href="https://somtoihezue.wordpress.com/">Somto Ihezue</a>, featuring cover art by Sejuti Bala. Stories by Amanda Ilozumba, Hussani Abdulrahim, and Ana Sun. Poetry by Mary Soon Lee and Abriana Tuller. Nonfiction by Nadia Benjelloun and Shantell Powell. Interior art by Jocelyn James, Joshua Effiong, and Martins Deep.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://solarpunkmagazine.com/shop/solarpunk-magazine-issue-10/" class="btn">Buy the issue →</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The City Walks Through You</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/the-city-walks-through-you/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/the-city-walks-through-you/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive-full.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T17:28:39+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive-full.jpeg" alt="" />
                    At the corner of The Causeway and Little Collins Street, she bent down and picked up a piece of broken heart that had fallen out of my pocket. The night breeze fluttered its frayed edges, the fragment trapped between her slender fingers—a lost butterfly. Her&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive-full.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>At the corner of The Causeway and Little Collins Street, she bent down and picked up a piece of broken heart that had fallen out of my pocket. The night breeze fluttered its frayed edges, the fragment trapped between her slender fingers—a lost butterfly. Her long hair left unwisely loose, chestnut strands billowed around her body, a soft veil threatening to tangle, never succeeding.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As an amateur street photographer, I've been a longtime practitioner of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D%C3%A9rive">dérive</a>, cultivating a habit of taking long, unplanned walks in whichever city I'm fortunate enough to find myself in. So when the invitation came from Todd Sanders of <a href="http://aanpress.com/">Air and Nothingness Press</a> to write a short story on the theme, I simply couldn't say no! </p>
<p>Like many of my Solarpunk stories, I want readers to be able to walk in a real city, follow the characters’ paths and imagine it as a different place. In the end, I settled on Melbourne, Australia, a very walkable city where I'd spent many, many hours wandering—just me, my camera and a battered notebook.</p>
<p><em>The Dérive</em> was edited by Todd Sanders and appears in a beautifully designed volume— complete with maps. Authors: Lyndsey Croal, Marie Croke, Cameron E Quinn, Ana Sun.</p>
<figure class="post__image align-center" ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/derive.jpg" alt="" width="351" height="535" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/19/responsive/derive-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
<figcaption >"The Dérive" book cover by Todd Sanders</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><em>This story has been set on a location on the lands of the Wurundjeri people, and we wish to acknowledge them as Traditional Owners and custodians. We pay our respects to their Elders, past and present.</em></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="http://aanpress.com/aanorder.html#derive" class="btn">Buy the book → </a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Write the Future You Want to Live In</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/18/Dreamforge-Anvil-11.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Articles"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T16:48:03+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/18/Dreamforge-Anvil-11.png" alt="" />
                    There’s a pretty good chance you’ve come across the oft-quoted anecdote on how the Star Trek communicator inspired the flip phone. This is usually preceded or followed by an assertion: because of this, speculative fiction has a place; we should keep writing it because it&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/18/Dreamforge-Anvil-11.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>There’s a pretty good chance you’ve come across the oft-quoted anecdote on how the Star Trek communicator inspired the flip phone. This is usually preceded or followed by an assertion: because of this, speculative fiction has a place; we should keep writing it because it has a genuine impact on the world. Turns out the second claim has support of some scientific evidence, but there’s more to the story...</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What makes Solarpunk a genre, and why should we write it? How do positive visions of the future affect both scientists and citizens, designers and engineers? Can fiction highlight solutions to environmental dangers and social injustice? </p>
<p>After encountering many questions that my writing colleagues seem to have, I pooled knowledge from solarpunk communities I've inhabited over the years and penned this evidence-laden article as a (hopefully) handy reference.</p>
<p>This article appeared online in <a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/magazines/details?id=36">DreamForge Anvil Issue 11: Solar Imaginings</a> and in print in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DreamForge-Magazine-Issue-12-Stories/dp/B0C6C4G6GN/">DreamForge Issue 12</a>.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://dreamforge.mywebportal.app/dreamforge/stories/show/write-the-future-you-want-to-live-in-ana-sun" title="Read 'Against the Time Beasts' on DreamForge" class="btn">Free to read →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/DreamForge-Magazine-Issue-12-Stories/dp/B0C6C4G6GN/" title="Buy print version of 'Dreamforge Winter 2023 Issue 11'" class="btn">Buy the print version →</a><a></a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Scent of Green</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/the-scent-of-green/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/the-scent-of-green/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/21/fightingforthefuture-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/21/fightingforthefuture-2.jpg" alt="" />
                    The problem was apparent even before Chloë could see the photobioreactors of Bluefirth—the distinct smell punched through the dappled daylight—a seashore's worth of dead creatures left for too long under a hot afternoon sun. One of my earliest attempts at writing Solarpunk, I wanted to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/21/fightingforthefuture-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<blockquote>
<p>The problem was apparent even before Chloë could see the photobioreactors of Bluefirth—the distinct smell punched through the dappled daylight—a seashore's worth of dead creatures left for too long under a hot afternoon sun.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>One of my earliest attempts at writing Solarpunk, I wanted to examine the challenges of knowledge sharing if communities were autonomous, self-reliant but fragmented— ideas I borrowed from past experience in grassroots activism.</p>
<p>This story appears in "Fighting for the Future: Cyberpunk and Solarpunk Tales" edited by <a href="https://phoebe-wagner.com/bio/">Phoebe Wagner</a>. Authors: Cory Doctorow, Brent Lambert, Ai Jiang, Jeremy Szal, Izzy Wasserstein, Louis Evans, Rona Fernandez, Lauren C. Teffeau, Kevin Wabaunsee, Holly Schofield, Commando Jugendstil and Tales from the EV Studio, J.D. Harlock, Ana Sun, Christopher R. Muscato, and Cynthia Zhang</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.android-press.com/product-page/fighting-for-the-future-cyberpunk-and-solarpunk-tales-ebook" class="btn">Buy the eBook →</a></p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="https://www.android-press.com/product-page/fighting-for-the-future-cyberpunk-and-solarpunk-tales-paperback" class="btn">Buy the paperback →</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Ana</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/about-ana/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/about-ana/</id>
            <category term="About"/>

        <updated>2023-01-01T17:07:42+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Ana Sun (pronounced “Soon”) writes from the edge of an ancient town along the River Ouse in the south-east of England. She spent her childhood in Malaysian Borneo, and has lived on two other islands prior to moving to the UK. In another life, she&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image page--author__avatar"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/ana-2014-hi-res.jpg" alt="" width="2803" height="2608" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-xs.jpg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-sm.jpg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-md.jpg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-lg.jpg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/17/responsive/ana-2014-hi-res-xl.jpg 1600w"></figure>
<p>Ana Sun (pronounced “Soon”) writes from the edge of an ancient town along the River Ouse in the south-east of England. She spent her childhood in Malaysian Borneo, and has lived on two other islands prior to moving to the UK. In another life, she might have been a musician, an anthropologist—or a botanist obsessed with edible flowers.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Contact Me</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/contact-me/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/contact-me/</id>

        <updated>2023-01-01T17:00:28+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Please say hi! Reach out to me via email or find me on Mastodon as @ana@wandering.shop. 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Please say hi! Reach out to me via <a href="hello AT singingtotigers.com" rel="nofollow">email</a> or find me on Mastodon as <a href="https://wandering.shop/@ana" rel="nofollow">@ana@wandering.shop</a>. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>La bibliothèque d&#x27;objets quotidiens</title>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Sun</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://singingtotigers.com/la-bibliotheque-d-objets-quotidiens/"/>
        <id>https://singingtotigers.com/la-bibliotheque-d-objets-quotidiens/</id>
        <media:content url="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-librarian.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Stories"/>

        <updated>2022-12-31T13:30:00+00:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-librarian.jpg" alt="The Librarian (standard cover)" />
                    Is there a moment that you would miss most, across any given lifetime? Sitting here in this hidden street in Montmartre—or at least the memory of it—might well be the moment I’d cling to at my final point of death. When Todd Sanders of Air&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-librarian.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="The Librarian (standard cover)" /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>Is there a moment that you would miss most, across any given lifetime?</p>
<p>Sitting here in this hidden street in Montmartre—or at least the memory of it—might well be the moment I’d cling to at my final point of death.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When Todd Sanders of <a href="http://aanpress.com/">Air and Nothing Press</a> made an open call for stories for <em>The Librarian </em>anthology, it came with <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/52625019/the-librarian-1">an intriguing list of character guidelines</a>. This story took inspiration from a real library of things local to me, mashed up with ideas triggered by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Doctor%27s_Wife">a favourite Dr. Who episode</a>. </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2.jpeg" alt="The Librarian (standard cover)" width="500" height="749" sizes="(min-width: 37.5em) 1600px, 80vw" srcset="https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-xs.jpeg 384w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-sm.jpeg 600w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-md.jpeg 768w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-lg.jpeg 1200w ,https://singingtotigers.com/media/posts/10/responsive/cover-202212-The-Librarian-2-xl.jpeg 1600w"></figure>
<figcaption >"The Librarian" (Standard Book Cover) by Todd Sanders</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><em>The Librarian </em>was<em> </em>edited by Todd Sanders. Authors: Azlïn Auckburally, E J Delaney, Jane Doring, Laurel Doud &amp; Katrice Marroquin, Indigo Emmerson, J.D. Harlock, CL Hart, A.P. Hawkins, Henry Herz, Storm Humbert, Larry Ivkovich, Carter Lappin, Kenzie Lappin, Anya Markov, Katrina Middelburg, Sean Monaghan, Waverly X. Night, Leo Otherland, D.G.P. Rector, Zachary Rosenberg, Elizabeth Snow, Ana Sun, Michael Teasdale, Nathan Waddell.</p>
<p class="align-right"><a href="http://aanpress.com/aanorder.html#TL" title="Order 'The Librarian' from Air &amp; Nothingness Press" class="btn">Buy the book → </a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
